你们的妈妈去世后 我突然想到了这些童年旧物
So, all this childhood memorabilia came to me after your mother died...
包括日记 相册 可爱的画
diaries, photo albums, adorable drawings.
好好享受你们的回忆之旅吧
So, enjoy your stroll down memory lane,
但请记住 那趟旅程的终点
but know that at the end of that lane
-是垃圾桶 -好吧
- is a dumpster. - Okay.
你在楼上放着一幅画
You have a painting upstairs
是绰号为"冰箱"的威廉·佩利的作品
by William "The Refrigerator" Perry,
但你却没地方存放我的乳牙
but there's no room for my baby teeth?
我需要在车库里腾出一些空间来
I needed to free up some space in the garage.
因为那已经不是车库了
Because it's not a garage anymore.
而是成了堆放没人买的狗床的仓库
It's a warehouse full of dog beds that nobody wants to buy.
最近销售是有些惨淡
It's been a slow period,
但下个季度应该会回升的
but it should pick up next quarter.
怎么回升
What?
等那些狗拿到薪资退税
When all the dogs get back their income tax refunds
就会非常豪爽地去给自己买床吗
and they want to go splurge on beds for themselves?
-乔 -什么事
- Joe. - What?
帮我拖一些这东西到我的车上去
Help me drag some of these things out to my car.
我们今天去做一些老式的营销
We're gonna do some old-fashioned marketing today.
天啊 我们以前的雅达利游戏机
Oh, my God. The old Atari.
还记得我们为什么会有这东西吗
Remember why we got that?
-当然 那是我们第一次享受家庭度假 -第一次
- Yeah. So, we were on our first family vacation ever, okay -- - Ever.
去一个水上公园度假一周
A week at this waterpark resort
-大概才三天爸就觉得无聊了吧 -三天
- and Dad got bored after, what, three days? - Three.
他强迫我们早早离开
Made us leave early,
给我们买了这个来收买我们
and he bought us off with this.
通篇谎言 纯属捏造
Lies and untruths!
我们在那里待了一整周
We stayed the full week,
我还是给你们两个不知感恩的家伙买了那个游戏机
and I got you two ingrates that game anyway.
你还要死不改口多久啊
How long are you gonna stick to that story?
只要你们两个继续把我描绘成
Much as you two enjoy portraying me
虐待孩子的家长 我就继续这么说
as some kind of abusive parent --
放松 乔 我们一会儿就救你出来
Relax, Joe. We'll get you out in a second.
都过去35年了 你还是不肯承认这事
Okay, 35 years, and you -- ugh, you still can't admit it.
-没什么好承认的 -我看到一道光
- There's nothing to admit. - I see light!
我该向它走过去吗
Should I go towards it?
如果不是事实 为何我们姐弟的记忆是一样的 爸
Why would we both remember it one way if it didn't happen, Dad?
小孩子就喜欢编造事情
Kids like to make things up.
他们喜欢那种狗血剧情
They like the drama.
快出来 小子
Come here, kid.
我都快咬断我自己的手臂逃出来了
I was literally about to gnaw my own arm off to get free.
就凭你这小牙齿吗
With those things?
我还保存着你吃棉花糖吃掉的那颗牙齿呢
I still have the tooth you lost in a marshmallow.
你倒是保存了他的牙齿啊
Okay, so, that one you kept?
我去了佛罗里达探望我的父亲
I was in Florida visiting my Dad.
我接到个电话 说他一直在
I'd gotten a call that he was wandering
他过去经营的那个杂货店附近游荡
around the grocery store he used to run.
我想搞清楚他是否没事
I wanted to find out if he was okay,
但是 这种事没办法直接询问
but...that's not something you can just ask.
你妈生前和我每个周日都会来这里
You know, your mother and I came here every Sunday
持续了44年
for 44 years.
你一定很想她吧
You miss her, don't you?
有时会想吧
It comes and goes.
-国庆节那天是最难熬的 -是吗
- Fourth of July is rough. - Really?
我以前都不知道她那么爱国呢
I didn't realize she was so patriotic.
是因为电视上播的那个热狗大胃王比赛
Well, it's that hot dog eating contest they have on TV.
我一直觉得你妈
You know, I always thought that your mother
可以去当大胃王选手
could have been a competitive eater.
我们家从来没有任何食物会过期
No food ever expired in our house.
她只要看到培根
She'd see that last day pop up
或牛奶还有一天就要过期了
on a pound of bacon or a gallon of milk,
就会全部吃下去
and down it went.
她不解决掉心里就不舒服
It was personal for her.
说到食物
Speaking of food,
你后来有没有再去过你那个旧杂货店
y-you ever head over to your old grocery store?
听我说 你还记得那个吗
Hey, listen. Do you remember that?
当然了 企鹅大脚怪
Oh, yeah. Penguinsquatch.
让这座小镇一时名声大噪
Put this town on the map.
1977年6月
June 1977.
一帮开狂欢派对的少年声称有巨大的鸟类脚印
Teen revelers report massive bird footprints
在奥基乔比湖湖岸上出现
emerging from Lake Okeechobee.
人们聚集围观
A crowd gathers,
但是涨潮把所谓的鸟类脚印都冲平了
but the new tide has covered the so-called bird prints,
那些青少年非常受挫
and the teens are beaten soundly.
几天后 又重新出现了这些脚印
Tracks reappear several days later,
再一次地 这消息传遍全镇
and once again, word spreads through town.
一位鸟类学家认为这些脚印
An ornithologist deems the prints
是巨型企鹅的 身高越有15英尺那种
those of a gigantic penguin, some 15 feet in height.
数英里外的人都闻风而来
People come from miles around
就为了看一眼那些神奇的企鹅
to catch a glimpse of the wondrous waddler.
那些脚印出现又消失 持续了好几年
The tracks will appear on and off for years
然后就彻底消失了
and then disappear forever,
但奥会员体操金牌得主玛莉·卢·雷顿
but not before Olympic gold medalist Mary Lou Retton
还是及时地远道赶来 将她的小脚印
makes the trek to place her tiny footprints
踩在了巨型企鹅的脚印里
inside those of the be-flippered colossus.
我们有好几个晚上在那里野餐过吧
Didn't we take a picnic over there a few nights?
大家都去了
Everyone did.
那是我第一次看到你妈吃了一整袋苹果
It's the first time I ever saw your mother eat a bag of apples.
那个 爸 我想问你...
So, Dad, I, uh, I w-- I wanted to ask you --
天啊 不要谈严肃的话题好吗
Oh, boy. No serious talk, okay?
是的 我服了一堆药
Yes, I'm taking all my million pills.
你可以过来按按我的肚子就知道了
You can come over and press my stomach.
我开始觉得自己跟豆袋椅一样了
I'm starting to feel like a bean bag chair.
各位 我刚看到一个鬼魂
Guys, I just saw a ghost.
好了 姑娘们 拿上东西 赶快逃命
Okay, girls, grab your things. We're gone.
不是真正的鬼魂
N-Not a real ghost.
确切地说 是过去的执念
More like a vision from my past.
布兰达·费德曼
Brenda Feldman.
那是曼尼曾经暗恋的一个小姐姐
An older girl that Manny had a crush on.
他小的时候 甚至还给她写过一首诗
He even wrote a poem for her when he was little.
我把我的心给了她
I gave her my heart,
她却送了我一张将我画成老式治安官的画
she gave me a picture of me as an old-time sheriff.
今天是我的第二次机会
Today was my second chance,
但我都没勇气去跟她打招呼
but I couldn't even get up the nerve to say "Hi."
11岁的曼尼一定会觉得我恶心至极
11-year-old Manny would be disgusted by me.
现在你明白12岁的莉莉当时的感受了
Well, now you know how 12-year-old Lily feels.
抱歉 是工作电话
Sorry, this is work.
喂
Hello?
曼尼 你知道这个大家庭里
Manny, you know who this family's
在人际交往问题方面的常驻专家是谁吗
resident expert is in interpersonal problems?
我觉得没人可以...
I would say no one's especially --
没错 正是在下
That's right. It's me.
虽然花了点时间 但我最终说服曼尼相信
It took a little while, but I finally convinced Manny
他上次跟布兰达·费德曼没成的原因
the reason he had failed last time with Brenda Feldman
就在于他用的大招
was because of his grand gesture.
今天需要采用完全不同的方法
Today called for a completely different approach --
超级大招
a super grand gesture.
直接去找她 明白吗
Just go to her, okay?
赶紧上场 冲啊 快
Get in there! Let's go! Come on!
驾
Hyah!
看来我的第一次房屋售卖要泡汤了
Well, looks like my first house sale is going to fall through.
亲爱的 我很遗憾 你知道吗
Oh, sweetie, I'm sorry. You know what?
一定会时来运转的
But things will turn around.
别转回来
Do not turn around.
那是黛布拉·诺克斯
That's Debra Knox.
她抢走了我的"年度最佳教育者奖"
She stole my Educator of the Year Award.
-"阴贼"吗 -影贼
- A swooper?! - A swooper!
-莉莉 拿上东西快逃 -不 不 不是
- Lily, grab your things. - Oh, no, no, no, no.
不是那种会吓坏农场小孩的"影贼"
Not a smoke demon that terrorizes farm children.
是指抢你东西的那种阴险贼子
It's a person that takes things that are supposed to be yours.
我就有个这样的对手
I have one of my own.
我那天就快完成第一次带人看房的工作了
I was closing a deal on my very first showing,
然后一个对手代理人俯冲而下
and a rival agent swooped in.
这房子真漂亮
What a lovely home.
不过或许有些不太适合孩子住
I mean, maybe not great for kids, you know?
等等 什么 我们就快生孩子了啊
Wait, what? But we're pregnant.
天啊 抱歉 我都没看到你们也在这里 我...
Oh, my goodness. I'm sorry. I didn't even see you there. I was --
天啊
Oh, my.
那是加州恶毒黄蜂吗
Is that a California vulture wasp?
肯定是有山狮刚刚在这里捕杀过猎物
A mountain lion must've made a fresh kill.
于是那对夫妻同意晚些时候去她代理的房子里参观
So, the couple agreed to go to her open house later.
♪ 嘿你好 苏 我听说你被甩了 ♪
♪ Hey, there, Sue, I heard you got dumped ♪
♪ 现在你很忧郁 ♪
♪ And now you are blue ♪
♪ 那么我们一起参加毕业舞会怎么样 ♪
♪ So, how 'bout we go to the prom ♪
♪ 前提是我妈她同意 ♪
♪ If it's okay with my mom? ♪
我好庆幸曼尼现在不搞丢人的这套了
I am so glad that Manny stopped doing those embarrassing things.
拜托 谁不喜欢看人放泡妞大招啊
Oh, come on. Who doesn't love a grand gesture?
当着我朋友的面干这种事 罗纳德
In front of my friends, Ronald?!
我真不敢相信我以前会让你帮我做作业
I can't believe I ever let you do my homework!
天啊 不 不 不要
My g-- Oh, gosh. Oh, no, no, Manny!
曼尼 取消 取消行动
Manny, abort, abort, abort.
取消行动
Abort!
退后 退后 退后
Back up! Back up! Back, back, back, back!
-快跑 快跑 -我在跑了
- Keep going! Keep going! - I'm going!
取消行动
Abort!
上周我留了一些狗床在这里
Last week, I left some dog beds here,
现在店家估计收到各种订购请求 忙不过来了
so now the owners are probably getting swamped with requests.
那天我发现
The other day, I found out
乔把六个月的零花钱都存了下来
that Joe saved up six months of allowance
全部捐给了慈善组织
and donated it all to charity.
作为父亲 这属于那种很罕见的时刻
It's one of those rare moments as a dad
就是你会觉得你很失败 没把孩子教好
when you realize you've really dropped the ball.
那孩子需要学会做生意的基本原则
I mean, the kid needed to learn the basics of business.
能把那只狗狗买给我吗
Ooh, can I get that dog?
我可以做50个小时的家务
I'll do 50 hours of chores.
不 100小时也行
No, a hundred.
销售第一课
Sales lesson number one --
在谈判时永远不要显得太急迫
never look desperate in a negotiation.
别带感情 想想你侄女莉莉
No emotion. Think of your cousin Lily.
我看到狗床卖了一些
Hey, I noticed the dog beds moved.
一定很受欢迎吧
They must be pretty popular, huh?
狗狗都不喜欢这些狗床
Um, the dogs didn't like them.
什么 那些都是没人要的狗啊
What? These are dogs nobody wants.
它们是什么情况 这么难伺候
I mean, what do they have going on?
别担心 猫很喜欢这些狗床
Don't worry. The cats love them.
猫 休想 我要把这些狗床拿回家
Cats? Never. I'm taking them home.
猫住在菠萝里 那根本说不通啊
I mean, cat in a pineapple? How does that even make sense?
或许是因为 它们来自"喵威夷"
Maybe...they're from Meow-I?
听懂了吗 夏威夷的梗
Get it? 'Cause Hawaii?
-上车去 -好的
- Get in the car. - Okay.
这个雅达利游戏机有个大凹陷处
This Atari has quite a dent in it.
-你当年用它砸过我吧 -没有的事
- Didn't -- Didn't you throw it at me? - No.
那你解释下我头上的这个凹痕 因为...
Then -- Then explain this groove in my head, 'cause...
你看 严丝合缝 能完美地拼合在一起
Yeah, I can -- I can fit them together like a puzzle.
米奇 你这伤是梦游时摔下楼梯造成的
Mitchell, you fell down the stairs sleepwalking.
那是我们家族遗传性的老毛病了
It's established family history.
不肯承认错误
Unwilling to admit a mistake.
真"好奇"你是从哪学来的呢
Wonder where you picked that up from.
听着 爸从不肯认错 也快把我逼疯了
Look, it drives me nuts, too, that Dad never cops to his mistakes,
但每次都是我们和他各执一词
but it's always gonna be our word against his.
-是啊 -你怎么把这些汗衫的领口都剪开了
- Yeah. - Why did you cut the necks out of all these sweatshirts?
我当年超迷《闪电舞》那部电影
Oh, I was a big "Flashdance" Fan.
你是怎么从霸凌的黄金年代活过来的
How you survived the golden age of bullying,
我永远无法理解
I will never understand.
等等 等等
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
我们面前就有一堆证据
We are sitting on a treasure trove of evidence
能够证明爸爸强行缩短了我们的假期 好吗
than could prove Dad cut our vacation short, okay?
你知道我的本职工作就是
I mean, you realize that building cases
利用证据来对付社会上最恶劣的罪犯
against society's worst criminals is what I do.
针对那个在湖人队比赛现场外
How's that case against the deaf old lady
售卖培根卷热狗的老太太的案子怎么样了
who sells bacon-wrapped hot dogs outside Laker games going?
已经事先警告过她三次了
She was warned three times.
好吧 我们要怎么证明爸爸强迫我们提早回来
Okay, how do we prove that Dad made us come home early?
我们去的那地方叫什么名字我都忘了
I mean, uh, what was that place we went even called?
等等 我刚看到一个火柴盒
Hold on. I just saw a matchbook from there, and --
找到了 在这呢 就是这个
Okay, yeah, yeah, yeah. Here it is, here it is.
"汉德曼水上公园 25周年纪念"
"Handelman Waterpark. Celebrating 25 years."
我也可以来当回犯罪现场调查员
I can get on this CSI train.
那地方建造于1958年 所以我们是1983年去的
Okay, "Founded in 1958," So that puts us there in '83.
查找我83年的日记
Locating my diary from '83.
-好极了 -很好 找到了
- Okay. - And okay. Here it is.
4月20日 "我觉得JT喜欢我
April 20th. "I think JT likes me.
他嘲笑我头上的凹陷"
Makes fun of my head dent."
好吧 所以度假肯定是在这之前
Alright, so it had to have been before that,
因为当时我们还没有那个游戏机
because we didn't have the video game yet,
所以那个凹...凹...
and that's what made the d-- the -- the --
我打断了你要说的话
I interrupted.
所以我们是4月初去的
So, we were there early April,
没有那个时候的日记记录
and, uh, no diary entries from then.
好吧 但这个或许有帮助
Okay. Okay. But maybe this might help.
瞧瞧这...
Look at...
这里 找到了
Here -- Here it is.
"在汉德曼的第一天"
"Day One at Handelman."
好 来吧
Okay, Here we go.
墨西哥流浪乐队都找来了
A mariachi band?
如果你想追到那个布兰达
If you want the Brenda girl,
装作不在意地和她说话
talk to her like you don't care,
-然后一周都别给她打电话 -怎么
- and then don't call her for a week. - Oh, oh, what?
让他把自己塑造成阴郁神秘的人
And present himself as some brooding mystery man
让她得努力博得他如父亲一般的认可吗
whose dad-like approval she has to work for?
哪个女人觉得那样有吸引力过啊
What woman has ever found that attractive?
我试试看
I'll try it.
太好了 又是黛布拉
Oh, great. There's Debra again.
她八成在下面臭显摆
Probably down there flaunting
她用我的奖赢得的30美元代金券
her $30 gift card she got with my award.
-那是我的奖 -要出击了吗
- It's my award. - Is it go time?
你知道吗 我这就下去
Yeah, you know what? Maybe I will.
我大步流星走到她面前
I'll just march right up to her,
用塔克的招牌盯人术鄙视她
and give her the classic Tucker stare down.
鄙视她 这就是你的大计划
A dirty look. That's your big plan?
是的 她会从我眼中看出
Yeah, she'll see in my eyes
我知道她都做了些什么
that I know exactly what she did,
相信我 不管这商场里
and trust me, all the free sample
有多少免费香水试用
of perfume spritzes in this mall
都遮不住她身上内疚的酸臭味
won't be able to cover up the stench of guilt on her.
我刚刚的闲谈很愉快
Well, I just made a nice little connection.
不是和布兰达聊的 她几乎没注意我
Not with Brenda, who barely noticed me,
是和罗纳德聊的 他邀请我去熊猫快餐
but with Ronald, who invited me to Panda Express
一起化心碎为食欲
so we could eat our feelings.
曼尼
Manny?
我电话号码还没给你 你就走了
Um, you took off before I could give you my number.
也把你的号码给我好吗
And maybe I could get yours, too?
-当然 -好
- Sure. - Yeah?
现在你的问题想要我的建议了吗
Do you need my advice with your problem now?
随便吧
Whatever.
你该一路往西开
See, you should point this thing west
来看看你的曾外孙们
and, uh, come meet your great-grandbabies.
开春了再去吧
Uh, this spring, I think.
我想让宝宝们重现有名的历史老照片
I want to pose them to re-create famous photos from history.
重现《胜利之吻》的服装我准备好了
I've got all the outfits, uh, to re-create the VJ-Day kiss,
但我还需要一顶软呢帽
but I still need the fedora
重现杰克·鲁比击毙李·哈维·奥斯瓦尔德
to pull off Jack Ruby and Lee Harvey Oswald.
-小心 -放心 枪里当然不会有子弹
- Careful. - Well, obviously, the gun won't be loaded.
不 不是 路面有坑
No, no, no. There's a pothole.
老天
Oh, geez.
车胎肯定瘪了
I bet we blew a tire.
幸运的是 某位本地发明家
Fortunately, one local inventor
一直在努力研发专利产品快速千斤顶
has been hard at work on the Presto-Jack TM,
该气动装置既能顶起车身
a pneumatic device that both lifts a car
又能为钻头提供更换车轮螺母的动力
and powers a drill to change lug nuts.
-该不会... -没错
- I don't suppose -- - Yep.
-就在后备箱 -太好了
- In the trunk. - Yes!
我们终于有机会试用了
We can finally test it out!
准备好发射了吗
You ready to launch?
开始吧
Let's do it.
特别稳 抬起来了
Steady as she goes, and she's up!
起效了 你成功了
It's working! You did it!
它 为什么还在上升
It's... Why is it still going?
你按开始键时很用力吗
How hard did you press start?
和那有什么关系
Well, that shouldn't matter!
-按"结束工作"就好 -好的
- Well, just press "End task." - Okay.
但只能按按钮的右半边
But only on the right side of the button.
你为什么不先告诉我
Why wouldn't you tell me that first?!
老天爷啊
Sweet maker!
所有人都警告过我会发生这种事
Everybody warned me this would happen.
黛布拉
Hello, Debra.
小卡
Hi, Cam.
想得美
You wish.
我知道你不会承认 但这双眼睛
I know you'll deny it, but these eyes...
能直接看穿你
can see right through you.
你是指我偷走了年度最佳教育者奖
You mean how I stole the Educator of the Year Award?
我让你承认了
I got you to admit it.
幸好我戴着录音设备
It's a good thing I'm wearing a wire.
-让我看看 -该死的
- Let me see it. - Damn it.
我会穿着这条裙子成为舞会之花
I'm gonna be the belle of the ball in this dress.
偷走这个奖让我有了自信
Stealing this award has given me the confidence
人挡杀人佛挡杀佛
to crush everyone in my path.
不好意思
Permiso.
我根本没见到歌洛莉亚进试衣间
I never even saw Gloria go into the dressing room,
可她就那样出现了 如超级英雄一般
but there she was, like a superhero,
一个亮相就能摧毁别人的自信
able to destroy confidence in a single pose.
我很高兴没买刚才那条裙子
I'm glad I didn't go with the first dress.
他们看一眼这条裙子 就会选我做校长
They'll take one look at this one and make me principal.
-搞什么 -你知道吗
- Aw, come on! - You know what?
或许你该试试那位女士穿的裙子
Maybe you should try the dress on that lady's wearing.
我的天 太天才了 我自叹不如
Oh, my God. That was brilliant and humbling.
我一直以帮别人解决问题而自豪
You know, I-I pride myself on solving people problems.
要知道 你的阴鬼也还没解决
You know what? You still have the swooper.
-或许我可以 -不必了 谢谢
- Maybe I could -- - No, thanks.
她只是不愿意让别人帮她 但我愿意
She just can't accept help, but I can.
我想穿这件大衣跟布兰达约会
I'm thinking about rocking this for my date with Brenda.
先别管这些纽扣
Ignore the buttons.
你能看出这是女式大衣吗
Can you tell this is a woman's coat?
能
Yes.
销售课第二堂课 创造需求
Sales lesson number two -- create demand.
到处放几张狗床 当狗狗爱上它们
Leave a few dog beds lying around, dogs fall in love,
你的电话就会响个不停了
your phones start ringing off the hook.
快去 快
Go ahead. Go.
我的狗狗特别喜欢这张床
My dog really likes this bed.
不知道放在这能不能创造需求
I wonder if leaving it here will create demand.
不用了 谢谢
Uh, no, thank you.
很好的开始
Alright, good start.
你本可以表现得更可爱些
You could've been a little cuter with that.
-什么 -你现在怎么说"特别喜欢"了
- What?! - When did you start saying "Really likes"?
怎么不说"尊稀饭"了
What happened to "Weawwy wikes"?
你请了语言治疗师来羞辱到我不说
You paid a speech therapist to shame it out of me.
还是没有信号
Still no cell service.
我们搭便车去理发店吧
Let's, uh, let's just hitchhike to the barber
在那打电话给拖车公司
and call a tow company from there.
你总是翻旧账
You can't let anything go!
你在我怀孕时跟我妹妹睡了
You slept with my sister while I was pregnant.
又不是性感的那个妹妹
Not the hot one!
我向天发誓 我向天发誓
I swear to God -- I swear to God,
我们一定要办完婚礼 这样等我杀了你
we are going through with this wedding so that I can kill you,
就能跟你的尸体办离婚了
and then I'm gonna divorce your corpse!
一看就知道是恩爱小两口
Well, you seem like a nice couple.
能让我们俩搭个便车吗
Room for two more in there?
我爸的乐观态度
My dad's positive attitude
对抗早晚闹出人命上新闻的情侣
versus a couple bound for a "Dateline" episode?
根本不是一个量级的
It wasn't even a fair fight.
♪ 甜蜜的卡洛琳 ♪
♪ Sweet Caroline ♪
♪ 叭 叭 叭 ♪
♪ Bup-bup-buh ♪
最后一课 总是做好转头走人的机会
Alright. Final lesson -- always be willing to walk away.
罗恩
Hey, Ron.
冲着咱们是老朋友我才先来找你
I'm coming to you first 'cause we're old friends.
-我叫朗恩 -行 听着
- It's Lon. - Yeah. Hey, listen.
这价格是有点贵
It's a steep price on this one,
但这不怪我
but don't blame me.
我的利润其实比做这个的童工还少呢
I'm pocketing less than the kids that, you know, made this thing.
比格犬号已着陆
The Beagle Has Landed.
抱歉 杰 这些都卖不出去
Sorry, Jay, none of these are selling.
长得像烤饼的那些也不行吗
Even the ones that look like hot cakes?
也许养只小狗能让你开心一点
Maybe a puppy will cheer you up.
我告诉过你了 不可能的
I told you, not gonna happen.
你要放弃了吗
You're giving up?
我根本送不出去这些东西
I can't give these things away.
忘了今天我教你的一切吧
Forget everything I taught you today.
我说的那些根本狗屁不通
I don't know what I'm talking about.
先生 我爸爸要给你
Hey, mister, my dad was about to give you
一次千载难逢的好交易
the deal of a lifetime --
一百块就可买到一百张狗床
100 dog beds for a hundred bucks,
这样你每卖一只狗就可送出一张狗床
so you can give one away with each new dog.
一百块 是吗
A hundred bucks, huh?
我看出来你没什么兴趣
I can see you're not serious.
别摇尾巴啦 伙计
Slow down that tail, buddy.
我要把它带走了
This is leaving with me.
慢着 别走啊
Wait, wait. Don't walk away.
五十块怎么样
Would you do 50 bucks?
那你能送我们一只小狗吗
Will you throw in a puppy?
我的晚年做了两个项目
I've had two late-in-life projects.
一个 狗床 是个失败
One, dog beds, was a bust.
另一个
The other...
看起来颇有前景
...is looking pretty promising.
好了
Alright, okay.
那么 汉德曼在99年倒闭了
So, Handelman closed in '99,
所以没有客人登记表能查何时退房的
so no guest registry to tell us when we checked out.
租车公司也是死胡同一条
Rental car companies are a dead end,
也没有信用卡收据
and no credit card receipts.
米奇尔 我们不得不认清现实了
God, Mitchell, it might be time for us to face some facts.
什么现实 上面有人
What? That some people very high up
不想让我们找到真相吗
don't want us to know the truth?
不 是我们得在这件事上放过爸爸了
No. That we might have to let Dad skate on this one.
想都别想
Never.
少吃点泡泡糖香烟 米奇尔
Go easy on those bubble-gum cigarettes, Mitchell.
对身体不好
They're gonna kill you.
听着 我们尝试过了 好吗
Look, we tried, right?
我买过这个泡泡糖香烟
I bought a pack of these
就在咱们待在酒店的最后一晚
the last night we were at that resort
当时我为了在我们去的演唱会上耍帅买的
so I could try to look cool at some... concert that we went to.
等等 它在哪儿呢 我
Hang on. Where was it? I --
中奖 你看到什么了
Oh-ho. Bingo. What do you see, huh?
我在公园 戴着帽子
Uh...um, me at the park in a hat
上面绣着"马多克斯"的名字
with the name "Maddox" embroidered on it.
我都把我的"马多克斯时期"给忘了
Oh, oh, I forgot about my Maddox Pritchett phase.
你不用每天被警察护送去学校
God, it is a miracle that you didn't need
真是个奇迹
a police escort to school every day.
不是看你 是看那个牌子
Not you, the marquee.
-"只有今晚和周三 猴子乐队" -没错
- Uh, "Tonight and Wednesday Only -- The Monkees." - Yes!
根据他们的网站来看
And according to their website,
他们是在14号和16号表演的
they played the 14th and the 16th.
所以 如果我们是第一晚去的
So, if we went the first night,
那就是说我们会在15号离开
that means we would have left the 15th,
也就是提前离开了
and we would have left early.
等一下
Okay, wait just a second.
我记得我很沮丧
I-I remember I was so upset...
-对 -我们的假期被砍掉了
- Yes. - ...that our vacation was being cut short
所以我为了让自己开心一点
that I cheered myself up
去看了《闪电舞》的首映
by going to the premiere of "Flashdance,"
那是在...
which was on...
有了 四月十五日
Ha! April 15th.
太好了 你对这电影是有多爱啊
Yea-- What is up with you and that movie?
她不仅仅是个焊工
She was so much more than a welder,
我也不仅仅是
and I was so much more than the president
反学生周间看电视组织的主席
of Students Against TV on Weeknights.
我知道你是这样记得的
Okay, I know you remember it this way,
但我们怎么证明呢
but how are we gonna prove it?
嘣
Bam!
我的票 清楚地写着"首演之夜"
My ticket, clearly marked "Opening Night."
我要再喊一声"嘣"了
I'm gonna say "Bam" Again.
-嘣 -天哪
- Bam! - Oh!
我简直不敢相信
I can't believe it.
我们终于可以看到爸爸
We might actually see Dad
承认是他的错了
admit that he was wrong! Ah!
我的天 我的天
Oh, my God, oh, my God!
你觉得他会哭吗 别
Do you think he'll cry? No.
克莱尔 别这样 默默享受成功就好
Claire, don't do that. Just take the victory.
为什么 为什么他要这么急着
I mean, why -- why was he in such a rush
回家啊 对吧
to get home, you know?
就为了去欧布莱恩酒吧见他的朋友吗
To -- To meet his buds at O'Brien's Pub?
我不知道 只是...
I don't know. It's just...
这个看起来有点奇怪
Well, that is a little weird, though.
上面写着 "致杰·普里契特
It says, "To Jay Pritchett,
世界上最伟大的酒保
the greatest bartender in the universe.
迪恩·马丁 1983年5月1日"
Dean Martin. May 1, 1983."
爸爸什么时候成酒保了
Since when was Dad a bartender?
等等 这就在我们的旅行之后
Wait, and this is right after our trip.
我给他工作搭档打个电话
I'm calling work wife.
你好
Hello?
你好 玛格丽特 打扰一下...
Hey, Margaret, really quick --
我爸曾经是酒保吗
was Dad ever a bartender?
天哪 谁知道呢
Gosh, who knows?
我反正是不会相信我的记忆了
I wouldn't trust this memory of mine anyway,
而且...
and --
信号好像...
This is a bad connec--
-玛格丽特 -你知道...
- Margaret. - You know --
手机上不再装天线的时候
...that's what a bad connection stopped sounding like
没信号就不是这个声音了
when phones stopped having antennas.
好吧
Fine.
你爸早年开公司的时候
Early days of the business,
我们发不出工资
we couldn't make payroll.
他不得不中断当时的旅行
He had to come back from a trip
自掏腰包来给员工发工资
to pay everyone out of his own pocket.
还要做夜班工作来补上缺口
Took the night job to make ends meet.
他怎么不告诉我们呢
Why wouldn't he have told us?
可能不想让你们担心吧
Probably didn't want to worry anyone.
总之 在穷途末路之际 他有了最佳的杰作
Anyway, back to the wall, he did some of his best work.
设计出卖得最好的衣柜
Came up with a best-selling closet.
《欢迎 马多克斯》
"Introducing the Maddox."
转角处就是家庭聚餐厨房
And around this corner is the entertainer's kitchen.
你在这里干嘛
What are you doing here?
我刚从这个不安全的后门进来的
Oh, I just came through the un-secure back door.
又见面啦
Hello, again.
你好 你的房子我们还是很有兴趣
Hi. We're still interested in your house.
只是我们可能会更倾向这间
We just might be leaning towards this one.
我真是太惊讶了
Oh, I'm very surprised.
像你们这样这么爱做饭的人
People that like cooking so much --
真的会满意这么小的食品储藏区...
are you guys going to be happy with this tiny, little pantry...
后面的这个这么大的储藏间吗
that leads to a gigantic pantry?
准备好要看看互动式育婴房了吗
Are you ready to see the interactive nursery?
宝宝兴奋地踢了一下呢
The baby just kicked!
你们好啊
Oh. Hey.
我们... 你们要成为我的新邻居了吗
We... Are you all about to be my new neighbor?
希望你们也喜欢开派对 我叫弗莱德
Hope you like to party. My name's Fred.
他们都叫我偷窥哥... 不过理由不重要啦
They call me Peeper because -- well, that doesn't matter.
你... 快来看 是巧克力碎饼干
Oh, you -- look, it's chocolate chip cookies!
孩子们 快进来
Kids, get in here!
快来这吃你们的晚饭
Get yourself some supper!
这两位是我的心肝宝贝
These are my blessings.
我是不是喜欢异族女子 我认罪
Do I like ethnic women? Guilty.
你们喜欢新鲜下的蛋吗
Do you like farm-fresh eggs?
我卖掉了我第一间房子并灭掉了我的阴贼
I sold my very first house and destroyed my swooper.
当然啦 唯一能灭掉真正影贼的方法
Of course, the only way you can destroy a real swooper
是在秋分前后的满月日刺死它们的影子
is to stab its reflection during the Harvest Moon.
祝你们在波兰愉快啊 两位
Enjoy Poland, you two!
弗兰克 我可能得关门了
Hey, Frank. Afraid I was about to close up.
-贝琪今天生日 -好吧 那我们下回再来啦 唐
- Betsy's birthday. - Okay, we'll come back, Don.
别 别着急 我的剪刀功夫还不错啊
Well, h-hang on. I'm -- I'm pretty nifty with the shears.
我以前都会帮卢克剪头发
I used to -- I used to cut Luke's hair,
有一次还把家里院子发现的刺猬
and I once trimmed a hedge in our yard
从刺猬头剪成明星的柔顺长发
into the spitting image of Doug Henning.
成功打动我
Sold.
-那你们好了帮忙锁门 -谢谢你啦
- Just lock her up. - Thank you very much.
请上座啊 少年
Hop on up there, young man.
要是我没记错 你人生第一次看到裸女
If I'm not mistaken, you saw your first naked lady
-就是在这间理发厅 -你很内行
- in this barbershop. - You know it.
很棒的交通指挥员 但一旦她开始发疯
Hell of a crossing guard, but when she went crazy,
她就会一条路走到底
she didn't go halfway.
毕竟人家职业就没有在走一半的
Well, that was her training.
老爸
So, Dad, um...
我就直言不讳了
just gonna get this over with.
天啊 你不会是要问我
Oh, boy. Is this gonna be
跑回去超市的那件事吧
about me going back to the grocery store?
毕竟事情真的有点奇怪嘛...
Well, it -- it just seemed a little weird.
我听说你在那里游荡了几个小时
I heard you were there for hours.
那里简直一团乱
The place was a mess.
超市人的荣誉心呢
I mean, where is the pride?
想当年 他们每周二都会外送橙子来给我
Old days, they used to deliver my oranges on Tuesdays.
就算有一万个希伯来奴隶
I could not have built a pyramid faster
我造金字塔也没那么快
with 10,000 Hebrews.
所以你其实不是在游荡吗
So, you weren't just wandering?
我只是... 我很想念以前的那一切
It's just -- I miss it, is all.
那我要问下一题了
This takes me to my next question.
你跟老妈有没有...
Um...did you and Mom ever --
想要过另一个孩子
ever want a-a-another child?
我想天下的父母都有好奇过
Well, I suppose all parents wonder
如果生的是不同的孩子 一切会变怎么样吧
how things would have changed if they had a different child.
我不是说有一个不同的孩子啦
I-I didn't -- didn't mean a different one.
我是说除了我之外 再有一个
I-I mean an additional one.
怎么会这么问
Why do you ask?
因为如果你有另一个孩子
Well, 'cause if you'd had another kid,
或许... 或许他就会接手你的生意
maybe -- maybe he'd have taken over the business
那你就不用把生意卖掉了
and -- and you wouldn't have had to sell.
我一直...
I always --
一直有点内疚我没接下来
I always felt kind of bad that I didn't.
菲尔 答案是没有 从没想过
The answer is no, Phil. Never.
因为...
Because...
其实你有把家庭事业接手过去啊 不是吗
well, you did take over the family business, didn't you?
保持快活人生 为所有人带来欢乐
Keeping life light, making it fun for everybody.
名师出高徒嘛
I learned from the best.
在我成长的期间 他一直是最酷的爸爸
When I was growing up, he was the cool dad.
他很潮
He was hip.
他会歌舞电影《油脂》中所有的舞步
He knew all the dances from "Grease."
他也熟悉各种流行语缩写
He knew all the expressions.
BFF 一辈子的死党
BFF -- best friends forever.
TMI 分享太多隐私了
TMI -- too much information.
BJ 蓝色牛仔裤[口交]
BJ -- blue jeans.
这让我一直觉得自己很幸运
It makes me feel lucky.
那天我们其实没做什么特别的 但...
We didn't do much that day, but...
或许那是我此生与我父亲共度过...
it might have been one of the -- the best days
最美好的日子之一吧
I ever had with my dad.
只是当时并不知道会是最后一天
I just didn't know it would be the last.
我爸走得安详
My dad was okay.
与他共处的那天让我学到的是
And my takeaway from our day --
不要错过对你喜爱的人表达爱的...
Don't miss a chance to let the people you appreciate...
机会
know that.
其实最难的东西呢
The hard part has been, um,
是要想出一个点子来向我爸致意
figuring out a way to pay tribute to my dad,
不过那天在车库里我终于来了灵感
but something came to me in the garage today.
我觉得他会喜欢我的点子
I think he would have liked it.
我的父亲 他留下的巨大足迹
He left some big footprints, my old man.
你看 他们处得很愉快
Look, they are getting along great.
这不是我们需要担心的
It's not our worry.
应该担心的是你妈
Your mother is.
八年了 她忽视斯黛拉 令她有心病
Eight years, she ignored Stella, and gave her a complex.
有一次我在咔咔按我的笔
One time I was clicking a pen,
斯黛拉都吐了
Stella threw up
因为她以为是你妈穿着高跟鞋朝她走来
because she thought high heels were coming.
我回来啦
Hola.
这是什么
What is this?
他才是负责的大人
He is the grown up.
亲爱的 我们知道你对...
Honey, we know how you feel...
这真是我此生最可爱的宝贝了
It's the cutest thing in my whole life.
我爱你
I love you.
天啊 我要跟我最乖的崽自拍 我马上回来
Oh my God, I need a selfie with my best little boy. I will be back.
不是你的错
It's not your fault.
这不是你的错